Martha Sharpe

Software Engineer

(701) 430-7151

marthasharpe2020@gmail.com marthasharpe.netlify.com

github.com/marthasharpe linkedin.com/in/marthasharpe2020

Summary

For the past 10 years, I have devoted myself to starting a family, managing a home business, and homeschooling four children. Last year, I took up web development and have been obsessed ever since. I have been specializing in JavaScript with React and Redux and have some experience with Node, Express, and MongoDB.

I love the daily challenges of web development: writing quality code, learning new technologies, and solving complex problems. I learn quickly and test my knowledge by creating projects, pushing to GitHub, and getting code reviews on LinkedIn. I was chosen as a LinkedIn Top Voice for Web Development in 2019 because of my contagious enthusiasm and passion for learning. I am eager to work on a team and put my skills to good use.

Tech Stack

JavaScript | React | Redux | Node | Express | MongoDB | Bootstrap | Git

Projects

MySchool: Full-Stack Website - https://my-school.netlify.com/

A website for saving online learning resources. Built a REST API using Node, Express, and MongoDB with Mongoose schemas. Implemented user login with password encryption and JWT authentication. Client-side is a basic CRUD application built with React. Used Redux for state management and redux-thunk for asynchronous API calls. Also used React-Router-DOM for dynamic routing and React-Bootstrap for styling. github.com/marthasharpe/myschool-back - github.com/marthasharpe/MySchool-front

Hangémon: React-Redux Game

An original game for kids and adults to guess the names of random Pokemon.

A React App using Redux for state management and Redux-thunk for the API call.

Mobile-first design using React-Bootstrap. Learned to control all aspects of the UI using state.

Hangemon.netlify.com - github.com/marthasharpe/hang-pokemon

Mix Master: JavaScript Game

A game to learn to mix cocktails. Original concept and design from my bartending days. I wrote this from scratch using ES6 JavaScript and styled it with CSS grid and flexbox. Used an object-oriented approach by creating a Drink class constructor.

Bartending-game.netlify.com - github.com/marthasharpe/Bartending-Game

Education

FreeCodeCamp, Online Certifications

2019

- Responsive Web Design (HTML5, CSS3)
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures (ES6)
- Front End Libraries (jQuery, Sass, Bootstrap, React, Redux)

University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND

2003-2007

- BA in Classical Studies, Honors Scholar
- Background in Calculus and physical sciences
- Graduated Summa Cum Laude

Work History

Homeschooling Parent, Self-employed - Atlanta, GA

2010-present

- Managed the accounts and logistics of a home-business
- Raised and homeschooled four children using Agile methodology
- Mastered time-management, prioritizing, and working under pressure

Head Youth Minister, Thomas Aquinas Newman Center - Grand Forks, ND 2009-2010

- Coordinated social and educational events for college students
- Delegated administrative duties to three other ministers
- Approached and engaged new students to make them feel welcome

Head Bartender, United Airlines Red Carpet Club - Arlington, VA

2008-2009

- Learned to mix 250+ drinks and track several orders at once
- Provided excellent customer service to business-class clientele
- Trained in Techniques of Alcohol Management

Karate Instructor, American Black Belt Academy - Colorado Springs, CO

2002-2005

- Earned my black belt and karate instructor certification
- Taught self-defense classes to children and adults at the main school
- Started a karate club in college as an official student organization